<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>surveillance on nrxr@journal:~$</title><link>https://nrxr.org/tags/surveillance/</link><description>Recent content in surveillance on nrxr@journal:~$</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nrxr.org/tags/surveillance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mass surveillance via facial recognition comes to latinamerica</title><link>https://nrxr.org/post/mass-surveillance-via-facial-recognition-comes-to-latinamerica/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:28:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nrxr.org/post/mass-surveillance-via-facial-recognition-comes-to-latinamerica/</guid><description>The Washinton Post reports on Buenos Aires&amp;rsquo; govt using facial recognition on minors and violating their privacy rights.
Main issues: inaccurate data in their database and inaccurate recognition in minors. There has been fights already in the UK against the usage of facial recognition by the police and in the US there&amp;rsquo;s been controversies and calls for bans.
Hopefully the same sentiment and approach is given in latinamerica where there&amp;rsquo;s less transparency on the government&amp;rsquo;s usage of data making the risk of misuse bigger and more threathening to individuals.</description></item><item><title>US collecting global data is an issue, China doing it with UN's permission is bigger</title><link>https://nrxr.org/post/us-collecting-global-data-is-an-issue-china-doing-it-with-un-s-permission-is-bigger/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nrxr.org/post/us-collecting-global-data-is-an-issue-china-doing-it-with-un-s-permission-is-bigger/</guid><description>The UN has given license and is encouraging China to use its surveillance system and collect data globally. The US doing surveillance and collecting data globally was an issue already, now China doing it is way worst.
China is a dictatorship and even when the US has been opaque about the data they are collecting and how is being stored we do know China is completely arbitrary and opaque. In the US there&amp;rsquo;s a separation of powers between institutions and a chance to actually clean up and learn about how the data is being used.</description></item></channel></rss>